Peters Oluwafemi

Javascript Programmer



+38063 702 9570

femipeters08@yahoo.com

Multi-faceted web developer who is knowledgeable in HTML/CSS, JavaScript, and Node.js, Meteor.js. A true team player offering 4 + years of experience in the Web Development. Seeking the opportunity to provide outstanding, clean code in a collaborative environment. Engaged in designing, developing, and managing complex we infrastructures

Detail-oriented, organized and meticulous employee. Works at fast pace to meet tight deadlines. Enthusiastic team player ready to contribute to company success.



Website optimization

Technical Analysis

Agile Workflow

Responsive design

JavaScript Programming

HTML5/ CSS3

Marketing

Troubleshooting

Programming Languages

Very Good

Excellent

Very Good

Very Good

Very Good

Excellent

Very Good

Average

Excellent

Good

CI/CD Modeling

PHP

Average

Good

API design knowledge

Excellent

Algorithm implementation





Work History

2021-01 - Lead Web Developer

2022-02

The Neighborhood, Kyiv, Ukraine

- Revised, modularized and updated old code bases to modern development standards, reducing operating costs and improving functionality.
- Introduced agile methodologies and development best practices to division to enhance product development.
- Assisted in business acquisition efforts by designing customized solutions for proposals to potential customers.
- Translated verbal requirements into written use cases and testable development stories.
- Provided front-end website development using WordPress, Hubspot and other editing software.
- Planned website development, converting mockups into usable web presence with HTML, JavaScript, AJAX and JSON coding.

2018-10 - Full Stack Web Developer

2021-12

The Neighborhood, Kyiv, Kyiv

- Designed and developed efficient and maintainable software according to business objectives and needs of various clients.
- Maintained complex technology infrastructure and collaborated with product team to implement new features and strategically plan for future products.
- Managed development milestones from initial steps through final delivery.
- Consulted with engineering team members to determine system loads and develop improvement plans.

2018-03 - Front End Developer Intern

2018-04

GoFriends, Kyiv, Kyiv

- Developed user interfaces with modern JavaScript frameworks, HTML5 and CSS3.
- Troubleshot and debugged code ensuring compatibility with devices, browsers, and operating systems.
- Designed and implemented web components across new and existing designs.
- Supported web applications and web sites through database development.
- Planned website development, converting mockups into usable web presence with HTML, JavaScript, AJAX and JSON coding.



Education

2014-09 - BE Or BEng: Aerospace Engineering

2018-06 National Aviation University - Kyiv, Ukraine

2006-09 - High School Diploma

2012-07 Folarin Dalley International College - Abeokuta, Ogun State, Nigeria



Accomplishments

- Built single-page applications with JavaScript on a Vue.js and Node.js
- Built web-admin panel for a client's game called Golden eggs
- Developed front-end for various websites, using libraries ranging from jQuery, Vue.js, Handlebars.js.
- Designed and developed GUI for applications and modules, using JavaScript, HTML/CSS.
- Worked on various applications required by the startup ranging from implementing of user accounts to other mainstream web apps built on Meteor.js on and microservices using Node.js and MongoDB
- Bachelor's Aircraft and Rocket Engineering



Languages

English





Russian

German

French

Basic

Basic